<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 13:30:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>3 Steps to packing and shipping more efficiently</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 13:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20728</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As a successful business owner, you’ll find that you never quite have enough time. Whether it’s making changes to your site, taking care of customers or just taking some time for yourself, there’s always more to be done. Today we’re helping you get back some of your time by showing you how to pack and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/">3 Steps to packing and shipping more efficiently</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a successful business owner, you’ll find that you never quite have enough time. Whether it’s making changes to your site, taking care of customers or just taking some time for yourself, there’s always more to be done. Today we’re helping you get back some of your time by showing you how to pack and ship more efficiently.<br />
<span id="more-20728"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">1. Identify bottlenecks</h2>
<p>The first step to improving any process is identifying bottlenecks. A bottleneck in this context refers to any activity that operates at a slower rate than all other activities in your operation. These slow-downs are generally easy to identify in warehouses because of the accumulation of orders that occur around  that operation. Depending on the complexity of your business activity, you may not have any bottlenecks or many! </p>
<p>If you don’t see any bottlenecks right away, try spending a few days observing how orders are processed. You’ll be able to spot any inconsistencies in the process that could use improving. If after a few days, you’re still unable to identify a specific bottleneck, consider ways to improve your entire operation instead. </p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">2. Refine the process</h2>
<p>If you have multiple bottlenecks, prioritize them from major to minor issues. You can choose to prioritize them by cost spent or time wasted. Organize it in the way that makes the most sense for your business. We’ll tackle the large issues first, because resolving larger issues may also clear up the smaller ones.</p>
<p>Find ways to remove the first bottleneck by improving the time it takes to complete the associated action or limiting the number of errors created. Ask yourself: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What part of this step isn’t necessary? What can I remove?</li>
<li>Can part of this step be completed later in the process?</li>
<li>Can part of this step be completed earlier in the process?</li>
<li>Can part of this step be combined with another task?</li>
<li>Is there a faster way to execute this task? </li>
<li>What additional resources can expedite this process?</li>
</ul>
<p>Keep this basic warehouse process in mind as we run through a couple of examples of how you can improve your business processes. </p>
<p><em>(1) Print packing lists → (2) pick orders → (3) print orders → (4) pack orders → (5) weigh package → (6) print shipping label → (7) off to the mailman</em></p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Removing a step</h4>
<p>If you’ve been with the company for a long time, this is generally the hardest solution to find. All tasks, even those that seem obvious to you, must be evaluated. For a new perspective, consider having a new trainee make these suggestions. </p>
<p>In the example listed above, consider the 1st task, print packing lists. If packing lists are not needed for your company, you can simply print orders forms and pack customer orders using that document. This cuts down on both the time and resources spent on printing the packing list. </p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Moving parts of a step</h4>
<p>There are some parts of your process that can be grouped with other tasks to maximize efficiency. Consider any action that takes away from the seamlessness of a process. For example, when  a product runs out while you’re packing orders, do you have to go and pull more inventory from storage? This is fine when you don’t run out of inventory, but if you run out of inventory multiple times during the day, it disrupts the flow of the process. Each time something runs out, the pack order process is paused so the inventory can be restocked.  </p>
<p>To make the order packing process more seamless, you create an inventory restocking process and move it the to the beginning of the day. It appears to add a new step to your overall process, but you’re simply defining a substep that is done regardless. By doing so, you clarify the overall process and make the order picking step more efficient. </p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Refining a step</h4>
<p>Sometimes it’s about improving upon a process that you already have in place. Sometimes you need to take a step back to see how you can make your process better. In our example, look at the “weigh package” step. If you already have the products on hand, you can weigh the product in advance and enter them in your PrestaShop store so that labels are automatically generated with the corresponding weights. This may not completely eliminate the “weigh package” step because you’re still weighing each product, but your order packing process is now more efficient. </p>
<h4 style="color:#eba32b">Additional resources</h4>
<p>Your last resort improvement is to call upon additional resources. This option should be considered last because it is not only more expensive to implement, but it’s bit like cutting corners to improve your shop’s efficiency. However, once you’ve exhausted all your options, it can be the only improvement left to make. If you find that all the steps are running as efficiently as they can, yet you’re still not able to fulfill orders on time, consider hiring another employee to help with the overall shipping process. Additionally, you can acquire new tools to expedite specific tasks. This can be anything from purchasing better printers to expedite the printing to or new carts to expedite order picking. </p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">3. Measure</h2>
<p>Once you know what you want to improve in your shop and how you want to approach the task, it’s time to implement. However, to know how well the changes are or are not working, you have to put some type of measurement tool in place. For example, you can measure the amount of time each step takes to complete. Additionally, you can count the number of orders processed each day. Either way, be sure you have something to compare your old process’s effectiveness against the new. </p>
<h2 style="color:#eba32b">In a nutshell</h2>
<p>Improving your shop’s operations is a continual process. There’s always new technology or ideas that can help you improve the way your shop works. All you need is a little time, some patience and a drive to want to be better. To make your business more effective: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Define your bottleneck, or problem</li>
<li>Refine that process and make it better</li>
<li>Measure your changes</li>
<li>Repeat</li>
</ul>
<p>What changes do you plan on making to your shop before the crazy holiday season? Let us know in the comments below. Already made some changes? Share some of the results you’ve found. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/">3 Steps to packing and shipping more efficiently</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-packing-shipping-efficiently/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Free Online photo editing tools</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20676</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When you sell online, your customers rely on images and text to make purchasing decisions. From product images and homepage banners to newsletter graphics, it’s important to have beautiful images that convince customers to convert. To help you get your images picture perfect, we’re sharing 7 free online photo editing tools. Online photo editing services [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/">7 Free Online photo editing tools</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you sell online, your customers rely on images and text to make purchasing decisions. From product images and homepage banners to newsletter graphics, it’s important to have beautiful images that convince customers to convert. To help you get your images picture perfect, we’re sharing 7 free online photo editing tools. Online photo editing services are great because you don’t need to download software. Additionally, you can access these services from any computer with an internet connection, which is perfect for entrepreneurs on the go.<br />
<span id="more-20676"></span></p>
<h2><a href="https://www.polarr.co/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">1. Polarr</a></h2>
<p>Polarr launched in 2014, making it one of the newest options available. It was founded by 2 Stanford students with a passion for art, photography and technology.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/1-polarr-1024x508.png" alt="1 polarr" width="700" height="347" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20678" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Endless color correction options.</strong> From basic features like saturation, temperature and tint, to expert functionalities like tonal curves and split toning.<br />
	<strong>- Guide to software features.</strong> With countless tools and features, it’s easy to get overwhelmed. They’ve got you covered with a <a href="https://www.polarr.co/guide" target="_blank">comprehensive guide</a> that includes examples and demos.<br />
	<strong>- Abundant photo presets.</strong> Pick from over 25 preconfigured photo edits fine-tuned to work with most images.<br />
	<strong>- Great for editing main images.</strong> The many options for adjusting color are perfect for editing banner images. The tools make it easy to give all your images a cohesive look that ties your online shop together visually.
</p>
<h2><a href="https://pixlr.com/editor/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">2. Pixlr</a></h2>
<p>Pixlr apps comes from Autodesk, the creator of Sketchbook, 123D, and Homestyler. The free version is supported by advertisements, but customers can opt for ad removal by paying $14.99 annually or $1.99 monthly. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/2-Pixlr-1024x611.png" alt="2 Pixlr" width="700" height="417" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20679" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left:30px">
	<strong>- Layers</strong> allow users to create composite images: you can merge two images into one or even give each of  your products a different background.<br />
	<strong>- Available in multiple languages</strong> including Spanish, French, German and Italian. This makes learning the function of each tool easier for non-English speakers.<br />
	<strong>- History option for undoing changes.</strong> Not happy with the changes you made? The history tab makes it easy to move back and forth between changes.<br />
	<strong>- Showcase.</strong> Each week, Pilxr sponsors a photo challenge. The best submissions are then featured on their showcase. It’s a great way to get your feet wet with photo editing, pick up new tricks and maybe even get your brand noticed.
</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.fotor.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">3. Fotor</a></h2>
<p>This powerful photo-editing suite comes with all the features you’d expect, like photo resizing and color correcting. However, this software is separated into 3 main functions &#8212; photo editor, collage creator and designer. To access premium designs and templates, simply create an account.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/3-fotor-1024x458.png" alt="3 fotor" width="700" height="313" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19385" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Great user onboarding</strong> makes it easy learn the features, so it’s super easy to get started.<br />
	<strong>- The collage function</strong> makes it easy to stitch together photos to make image compilations. If that’s not cool enough, you can easily add stickers to give your images more character.<br />
	<strong>- Social media templates</strong> help you create engaging pictures for your social media pages. Best of all they’re sized correctly so you never have to worry about whether your image will work on a specific platform.<br />
	<strong>- Their YouTube Channel</strong> provides walkthroughs that help you create images for your online shop. Check out their latest <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/back-school-basics-every-online-merchant-know/">“Back to School”</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zajtO-LUO1Q" target="_blank">poster tutorial</a>.
</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.canva.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">4. Canva</a></h2>
<p>Launched in Australia Canva raised over $3.6 million to launch a beta version in 2012. To date, they have close to 5 million users worldwide. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/4-Canva-1024x510.png" alt="4 Canva" width="700" height="348" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20681" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	- With over <strong>40 pre-made templates</strong>, you can design anything from social media headers and posts to invitations for all types of events.<br />
	<strong>- A <a href="https://designschool.canva.com/" target="_blank">Design school</a></strong> walks you through all types of design-related topics including infographic design, design layout and even color theory.<br />
	<strong>- 3rd party stock images</strong> are readily available for purchase, directly from the platform. This is perfect if you’re missing one last thing to complete your design.<br />
	<strong>- Frequent updates</strong> means you’ll get the latest design trends built in. If Facebook adds a new image size, you know you’ll have the template on the site soon.
</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.picmonkey.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">5. PicMonkey</a></h2>
<p>Love Picnik? You’ll love PicMonkey. After Google acquired and later disbanded Picnik, the founding team worked together to create this platform. It’s functionality includes photo editing, graphic design and collage making. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/5-PicMonkey-1024x500.png" alt="5 PicMonkey" width="700" height="341" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20682" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Great for beginners.</strong> Of all the platforms we mentioned, this is by far the simplest to use.<br />
	<strong>- Lots of pre-set filters</strong> make it easy for you to give all your pictures the same look and feel. Simply click on a filter to apply it, then use the new window to make slight adjustments.<br />
	<strong>- Lots of themes</strong> to pick from to add a little holiday spirit to your shop. Its perfect when you’re decorating your shop and interacting on social media.<br />
	<strong>- Collage option</strong> for stitching images together. It’s pefect if you’re compiling images, especially when you want to feature multiple images that are quite similar (like ones from an event.)
</p>
<p>To take advantage of their premium features, simply upgrade for either $4.99/month or $33/ year. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.ribbet.com/app/?picnik#/edit/basic" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">6. Ribbet</a></h2>
<p>When Google closed Picnik in 2012, the founding team set out to offer clients a comparable solution. They offer a free version of their service that users can easily upgrade to access more functionality. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/6-Ribbet-1024x457.png" alt="6 Ribbet" width="700" height="312" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20683" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Add your favorite features</strong> to a tab so you can easily access them each time you edit a picture.<br />
	<strong>- Edit pictures from your social media accounts</strong> without having to re-download them to your shop.<br />
	<strong>- Turn pictures into products</strong> with integrated sites like Zazzle and MILK. Directly upload your designs into the platforms to purchase custom mugs, shirts or even photo books.
</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.befunky.com/" target="_blank" style="font-size: 28px;font-family: 'Roboto Condensed',Tahoma,Verdana,sans-serif;color:#02bddc">7. BeFunky</a></h2>
<p>Just like many of the tools mentioned in this blog, BeFunky offers a completely free version with the option to upgrade for $4.95/ month or $24.95/year. There are also sections for photo editing, collage making and design. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/7-BeFunky-1024x510.png" alt="7 BeFunky" width="700" height="348" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20677" /></p>
<p>Here’s what we love: </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">
	<strong>- Specific tools</strong> for each function helps you narrow down the features you’ll need for each type of editing need. For example, the design tab gives you easy access to templates that are perfect for each social media platform.<br />
	<strong>- No ads and a minimized menu</strong> gives way to a large editing area so you have more screen space dedicated to photo editing.<br />
	<strong>- Mobile versions available.</strong> The software is not just available online; you can also download it from from the App store and Google Play.
</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Ready to revamp you shop? Upload the new images you’ve made. Not sure what the size requirements are? Check out this blog post for <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/image-sizes-types-prestashops-default-template/">image size and types for PrestaShop’s</a> default template. Already using one or many of the free online editing software we listed? Let us know which is your favorite in the comments below. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/">7 Free Online photo editing tools</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-free-online-photo-editing-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to consider when choosing payment options</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camille Sila]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>There are a million things to think about when you start a new online shop. You&#8217;ll probably spend a lot of time thinking about design, how your products or services are presented and how to attract traffic to your website. Additionally, you’ll be thinking about how to achieve a high conversion rate for your customers [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/">What to consider when choosing payment options</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are a million things to think about when you start a new online shop. You&#8217;ll probably spend a lot of time thinking about design, how your products or services are presented and how to attract traffic to your website. Additionally, you’ll be thinking about how to achieve a high conversion rate for your customers to check out or to register. You may also find it a challenge to select the right mix of payment options to offer to your customers – and your selection should take your customers&#8217; needs and the costs and level of security of each payment method into consideration.<br />
<span id="more-20640"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#ea5c2a">Various options for various requirements</h2>
<p>Studies show that around 88 percent of all potential buyers leave an online shop if the only payment option offered is advance payment. By integrating further payment methods, the purchase abandonment rate can be reduced to 1%. Successful online merchants predict that in the next five years PayPal, credit card (with and without 3-D Secure protection), and &#8220;payment through invoice&#8221; will gain further customer importance (ibi research, 2015, University of Regensburg). </p>
<p>Apart from customer acceptance, merchants also need to compare the direct costs of a payment method as well as potential indirect costs. For instance, the University of Regensburg found out that for &#8220;purchase on account&#8221; other costs increased the direct costs such as those from late payments, payment irregularities, defaults, and even encashment procedures. </p>
<p>Last but not least, security plays an important role in the payment method selection process: on the one hand merchants want to establish customer trust by protecting sensitive payment data (e.g. thanks to encryption), and on the other protect themselves by applying fraud prevention measures for each payment method.  </p>
<h2 style="color:#ea5c2a">Support from experienced Payment Service Providers</h2>
<p>Online businesses should spend their IT resources on their own products rather than dealing with online security requirements. They can rely on payment service providers who offer different options for accepting different payment methods. Startups, and small and medium-sized businesses can benefit from the know-how of payment service providers. To serve merchants with maximum security, providers should be PCI-certified (Payment Card Industry). </p>
<p>Because online shops are at risk of fraudulent behaviour, payment service providers usually apply additional fraud prevention measures. Automated risk checks and encryption of sensitive payment information help ensure online shops do not fall victim to fraudulent abuse, and reduce financial damages. </p>
<h2 style="color:#ea5c2a">About PAYMILL</h2>
<p>PAYMILL is a PCI-certified payment service provider which makes it easier for online businesses to process credit card payments. The <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/payment/paymill">free PAYMILL module</a> offers an easy way for integrating card payments into your PrestaShop. PrestaShop merchants receive the access data for the module by registering and activating a free PAYMILL account. Merchants benefit from a flexible technical solution which allows designing their own payment and which offers the optional usage of the 3-D secure protection feature (known as Verified by Visa or MasterCard SecureCode). All these features help merchants increasing their conversion rates. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/">What to consider when choosing payment options</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/consider-choosing-payment-options/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>9.5 ways to participate in the PrestaShop Community</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20672</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking for ways to participate in the PrestaShop community? Here are nine ideas! As you may know, we dedicated our new mascot, Preston the puffin, to our community. This little bird is not just resourceful, but survives by living in large communities. Read on to see how you can contribute your best skills to helping [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/">9.5 ways to participate in the PrestaShop Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for ways to participate in the PrestaShop community? Here are nine ideas! As you may know, we dedicated our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/preston/" target="_blank">new mascot, Preston</a> the puffin, to our community. This little bird is not just resourceful, but survives by living in large communities. Read on to see how you can contribute your best skills to helping the community thrive.<br />
<span id="more-20672"></span><br />
1. <strong><a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/PrestaShop" target="_blank">Code on GitHub</a></strong><br />
Speak PHP? Help add functionality or create a seamless user experience by contributing code on GitHub. Without the help of our contributors, we wouldn’t have a growing list of over 300 features &#8212; offered at no charge!</p>
<p>2. <strong><a href="https://crowdin.com/project/prestashop-official" target="_blank">Translate with CrowdIn</a></strong><br />
Speak a second language? Help us translate PrestaShop into your native language on CrowdIn. Not interested in writing copy? Vote on translations others have submitted. To date, our community members have already helped make PrestaShop available in: Bulgarian, Croatian, Dutch, Norwegian, Slovenian and Swedish.</p>
<p>3. <strong><a href="http://forge.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Forge</a></strong><br />
Have an idea for a software feature? Or have a bug you’d like to report? Search for and submit your request on our Forge. Each ticket is reviewed by a member of our team then prioritized.</p>
<p>4. <strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/forums/" target="_blank">Forum</a></strong><br />
The PrestaShop forum is one of the most active ecommerce communities around the world. With more than 800,000 members, conversations happen in a multitude of languages including English, French, Spanish and Italian.</p>
<p>5. <strong>Give us feedback on our documentation</strong><br />
On most pages of your PrestaShop Back Office, you’ll find a help section dedicated to helping you use that website. At the bottom of the help section, please leave us some feedback. This helps us understand what information is useful and what we need to add or remove.</p>
<p>6. <strong>Build themes</strong><br />
PrestaShop merchants are always on the lookout for the latest design trends for their website. If you like to create new designs, run the code through our <a href="https://validator.prestashop.com/auth/login" target="_blank">code validator</a>, then start selling them on <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/content/25-how-to-sell-on-prestashop-addons" target="_blank">PrestaShop addons</a>, and watch your earnings roll in!</p>
<p>7. <strong>Build modules</strong><br />
Just like with themes, you can build your own modules with specific functions. Need help funding your project? We launched an integration fund dedicated to helping our community innovate and create modules that are adapted to each local market. Find out what we’re looking for, then <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/integration-fund" target="_blank">apply online</a>.</p>
<p>8. <strong>Join our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/club/" target="_blank">User Club</a>!</strong><br />
Want to share your experience and opinions with the PrestaShop product team? Join our User Club. Each month, we’ll send out a short survey to about an ecommerce-specific topic. In exchange, you’ll get sneak peeks about what’s coming up next.</p>
<p>9. <strong>Become a <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Ambassador</a> </strong><br />
Do you want to become a local representative for PrestaShop? We’re enlisting your help to host local meetups, give us product feedback, publish guest blog posts and more. Apply to be an Ambassador today. If selected, you’ll get our support and maybe even some swag.</p>
<p><strong>9.5</strong> Too busy running your online shop to actively participate? You are still part of our community. You read our blogs, share them on social, leave comments, subscribe to our newsletter and even follow us on social media. Regardless of how you choose to participate, we’re glad you’ve come along for the ride!<br />
____</p>
<p>Are you already playing a major role in our community today? Thank you for your contributions! Not an active member of our community yet? What are you waiting for? Join the largest international ecommerce community today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/">9.5 ways to participate in the PrestaShop Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/9-5-ways-participate-prestashop-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 07:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20653</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the best features we added to PrestaShop v1.6 is the analytics dashboard. Not only is it one of the most appealing pages, it’s one of the most helpful when it comes to growing your business. Today we’ll break down the stats and share a few tips on how you can get the most [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/">Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the best features we added to PrestaShop v1.6 is the analytics dashboard. Not only is it one of the most appealing pages, it’s one of the most helpful when it comes to growing your business. Today we’ll break down the stats and share a few tips on how you can get the most out of them. Let’s get started!<br />
<span id="more-20653"></span></p>
<p>The first stats are often referred to collectively as KPI’s, or key performance indicators. Most companies use one or several of these statistics to evaluate their store’s overall performance compared to industry standards or past store performance.</p>
<h2 style="color: #86acc0">Dashboard</h2>
<p>The first chart you’ll see when you open your shop is your dashboard. Below we explain how each stat is calculated, what it tells you about your shop, and how the number can be skewed.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20664" alt="Bo" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/Bo.gif" width="972" height="497" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Sales</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all order totals)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>This number is pretty straightforward &#8211; it shows you how much money your shop is making. Hopefully, you’ll see an upward trend: in other words, your shop is making more money this month then it did the previous month. An upward trend shows your shop is growing and converting more customers, while a downward trend shows that customers are not purchasing as much or as often.</p>
<p>However, merchants generally see increases and decreases from month to month. The holiday sales season is a perfect example: strong holiday sales are often followed by a high number of returns.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Orders</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Number of orders received)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>It’s important to know the number of orders that your store receives, because it indicates the number of customers you are successfully converting. Ideally, you’d like to see an upward trend here, too. However, don’t be surprised if you find that this number dips during slower months. You can easily compare each month’s performance against numbers from the previous year to continually evaluate your store’s growth.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Cart Value</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sales / Orders)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Average cart value indicates the average amount that a customer spends on each visit to your site. <span style="text-decoration: underline">Cross-selling and upselling features have proven to effectively increase this number</span>. However, being too focused on increasing cart value can also hurt your shop. Be sure you’re promoting not just larger orders, but more orders. An increasing number of orders of increasing value is your ultimate goal.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Visits</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all traffic to your website)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Visits are a number game: the more people browsing your shop, the more likely you are to make a sale. Even when you don’t close a sale, your chances of converting that visitor one way or another, increase. <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/">Well-designed lead magnets</a> are a great way to engage your customers, even before they make the decision to purchase. However, a large number of visits can be attributed to “bots” scanning your website. The overstated number of visits can decrease other stats like conversion rates.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Conversion Rate</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of orders / sum of visitors)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Conversion rates give online merchants a good sense of how many visitors actually complete purchases. This metric is especially useful for merchants who are trying to optimize their website design. During A/B tests, conversion rates help merchants decide which final design should be used.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Net Profit Margin</strong> <span style="font-style: italic">(Sum of all revenue &#8211; sum of all expenses)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>This statistic is one of the most important numbers online merchants should analyze. It clearly shows how much money your business has gained or lost. By filling in fields like wholesale price, bank charges and shipping fees, PrestaShop gives you an up-to-date estimation of your business’s financial standing.</p>
<h2 style="color: #86acc0">Products and Sales</h2>
<p>At the bottom of your dashboard page, you’ll find the product and sales table. It’s a quick summary of the information provided on your stats tab. We’ll detail what information each of the following tabs provides and how you can leverage that information.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20665" alt="product_sales" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/product_sales.gif" width="835" height="437" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Recent Orders</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This tab shows you the most recent orders placed on your website. It also details who made the purchase, the order size, and even the number of items purchased in the order. You’ll have a good idea of how busy or not busy, the business is. When you’re managing a team, it’ll help you decide how you should organize the staff and their responsibilities.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Best Sellers</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This tab simply shows you which products have been selling the best over the specified period of time. It’s worth noting if a specific image color or product category gets the most sales. Consider staging your images to mirror your best sellers or even purchasing more products that fall within the most-popular category.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Most Viewed</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This section simply lists the products that have been viewed the most by customers. Make sure you configure your back office to present the right numbers. Once you know which product is the most popular, match it against your best sellers list. Ideally the products should be similar. After all customers are more likely to purchase a product they’ve seen than one that they have not. If items on your most viewed list did not make the best seller list, consider adjusting the price to get customers to convert. Also keep in mind that a product’s merchandising may also play a role in how it’s viewed. For example, is the product currently listed on the homepage?</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Top Searches</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This table lists the top searches from customers browsing your website. It’s key to understanding what your customers are looking for when they visit your website. First, try searching each of these terms yourself to ensure they produce accurate results. If the search terms aren’t necessarily what you’re used to, consider adding them as “tag” to help customers find the product. Here are <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-essential-tips-to-improving-your-on-site-search-engine/">4 essential tips to improving your on-site search</a>.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>If you’re already using your PrestaShop back office dashboard, which stats do you refer to the most? Want to take a live tour of our dashboard? Check out the <a href="http://demo.prestashop.com/en/?view=back">PrestaShop demo</a>, then launch your own free <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/create-your-online-store">PrestaShop store</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/">Getting the most out of your back office stats dashboard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/getting-back-office-stats-dashboard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays just around the corner, you’re probably trying to come up with a few easy ways to increase your average cart value and capture more holiday sales. Sometimes the solution can be super simple &#8211; as simple as improving the appearance of gift packages. Today we’re sharing 5 gift wrapping ideas to help [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/">5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays just around the corner, you’re probably trying to come up with a few easy ways to increase your average cart value and capture more holiday sales. Sometimes the solution can be super simple &#8211; as simple as improving the appearance of gift packages. Today we’re sharing 5 gift wrapping ideas to help boost your holiday sales!<br />
<span id="more-20645"></span><br />
The <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/12/wrappers-delight-a-brief-history-of-wrapping-paper/266599/" target="_blank">history of wrapping paper</a> spans the globe, from Japan, where furoshiki, reusable wrapping cloths have been used since the 17th century, to Victorian Britain where gifts were hidden with decorative paper, ribbons and lace. Wrapping gifts is a common practice around the world, and for online shops, it can easily be adopted to improve the customer experience and increase bottom lines. Customers purchasing gifts that will be shipped directly to the recipient appreciate the option. </p>
<p>Here are a few ways to make your gift wrapping options stand out. </p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">1) Personalized Note Card</h2>
<p>The first way to personalize an order is by including a card that shoppers can customize with a short message. Consider <a href="http://www.moo.com/us/products/greeting-cards.html" target="_blank">printing custom greeting cards</a> with your company’s logo and branding. Keep in mind that customers may celebrate different holidays than you do, so note card design should be festive but neutral. They’re simple to include in the order packing process because all you have to do is drop the card in the box!  Although you can choose to hand-write these notes, printing the text ensures readability and reduces errors.</p>
<p>This is a great option if this the is the first time you’ve thought about adding gift wrap. It’s relatively easy to implement  it doesn’t take too many supplies. To keep costs low, opt for a simple postcard without an envelope.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">2) Box with ribbon</h2>
<p>A box with a ribbon is a standard way to wrap a present. Just think of Tiffany’s iconic blue box and white bow <a href="http://www.tiffany.com/WorldOfTiffany/TiffanyStory/Legacy/BlueBox.aspx" target="_blank">Tiffany’s</a>. To include  this gift packing option, pick a box size that would fit a normal order. The order should fit snugly, so the gift doesn’t move around in transit. If your products come in a variety of sizes, consider having a few different boxes on hand. For a cute and custom design, <a href="http://us.selfpackaging.com/91-gift-boxes" target="_blank">PrestaShop store Self-Packaging</a> offers a large variety of gift packaging for all types of items.</p>
<p>Another key thing to consider is how you’ll add the gift wrap into your packing process. Consider pre-measuring the ribbon or dedicating one person to gift wrap so that your regular orders are processed consistently. Keep in mind that these gift boxes with a pretty bow should fit in your regular shipping box, making this option pricier to implement.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">3) Printed Gift Boxes</h2>
<p>Similar to a box with ribbon is a printed gift box, with one noteworthy difference: it doesn’t need to be shipped inside another box. <a href="http://www.uline.com/BL_5603/Apparel-Boxes" target="_blank">Uline offers a wide variety of pre-printed gift boxes</a>. This affordable option simplifies the packing process because all you have to do is replace the original box with the new decorated box. And just like with the note card, gift box design should be neutral to accommodate a wide variety of holidays.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">4) Decorative Mailers</h2>
<p>If repacking your order into boxes is out of your budget, you can opt to mail presents in prettily designed mailers. There are 2 types: <a href="http://www.scotchbrand.com/wps/portal/3M/en_US/ScotchBrand/Scotch/Products/Catalog/~/Scotch-Plastic-Bubble-Mailer?N=4335+5584761+3294580325&amp;rt=rud" target="_blank">bubble mailers</a>, which are great for items easily damaged during transit, and self-sealing poly bags. Compared to the regular mailers, decorative mailers look more fun and festive. Mailers are even easier to use and implement than gift boxes and ribbons.</p>
<p>This same concept can also be applied to products shipped in large envelopes or sleeves. There are countless vendors that offer decorative versions of these shipping materials.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5e338c">5) Custom Tissue paper</h2>
<p>Another quick way to implement gift wrapping is to add <a href="http://www.uline.com/CustomStaticTissuePaper.htm" target="_blank">custom tissue paper</a>, which you can order in bulk and have customized with a color and your logo. You don’t have to make any changes to the shipping box; you’ll just slip some pretty tissue paper into your standard shipping box. If you want to upgrade the tissue paper, seal the tissue with a sticker that features your logo.</p>
<p>No matter which gift wrapping options you offer, it’s important to include a packing list &#8211; a document that details the order without listing prices. This makes it easy for the gift recipient to make exchanges or returns and for you to processes these orders.</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Do you currently offering gift wrapping on your site? Tell us what worked best on your shop. Not yet offering gift wrapping? Share with us the options you’ll start offering. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/">5 Easy Ideas for Gift Wrapping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-easy-ideas-gift-wrapping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Countdown to the holidays</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20632</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Summer is rolling to a close, which means another season is on it’s way: the holiday season. For retailers, it’s the start of the year’s busiest sale period. Many merchants are already knee-deep in their “Back-to-school” sales. If you’re still recovering from vacation, don’t worry: our countdown to the holidays will get you in shape [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/">Countdown to the holidays</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Summer is rolling to a close, which means another season is on it’s way: the holiday season. For retailers, it’s the start of the year’s busiest sale period. Many merchants are already knee-deep in their “Back-to-school” sales. If you’re still recovering from vacation, don’t worry: our countdown to the holidays will get you in shape for the 2015 holiday season.<br />
<span id="more-20632"></span><br />
You can choose to promote a sale during each of the holidays we mention below, or just the ones you personally celebrate. Either way, be sure you plan everything in advance so your sales smoothly and without a hitch!</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_september-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_september" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19342" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">September</h2>
<p><strong>Labor Day</strong> &#8211; (Sept 7th) Wrap up the summer season with a Labor Day Sale. This long weekend is the perfect opportunity to convert customers and clear out your summer inventory to make room in your warehouse for holiday shipments. </p>
<p><strong>Rosh Hashanah</strong> &#8211; (Sept 13th) This Jewish holiday celebrates a new year. Those who celebrate it often receive money rather than gifts, so consider offering gift cards for the occasion. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_october-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_october" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19341" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">October</h2>
<p><strong>Halloween</strong> &#8211; (Oct 31st) This eerie holiday may seem like it’s only for brave souls. However, merchants can also take advantage of Halloween, especially those that include costumes, candy and creepy decorations in their product catalogs. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_november-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_november" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19340" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">November</h2>
<p><strong>Thanksgiving</strong> &#8211; (Nov 26th) Turkey, gravy and sweet potato pie: nothing says Thanksgiving better than overindulging in food with those you hold dear. When all the food has settled and the football game is won, families get into the holiday spirit by decorating their homes for Christmas. </p>
<p><strong>Black Friday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 27th) A sale day that traditionally starts the morning of the Friday following Thanksgiving; however, as large retailers have become increasingly competitive, Black Friday sales have been starting earlier and earlier each year. <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/black-friday-store-hours-2014-2014-11" target="_blank">In 2014, some sales started as early as 5:00PM on Thanksgiving</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Small Business Saturday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 28th) Supported by the Small Business and Entrepreneurship Council, Small Business Saturday encourages people to #shopsmall. If you own a retail location, check out these four ways to prepare for <a href="https://www.sba.gov/blogs/5-ways-prepare-small-business-saturday" target="_blank">Small Business Saturday</a>. </p>
<p><strong>Cyber Monday</strong> &#8211; (Nov 30th) Cyber Monday is to online retailers what Black Friday is to brick and mortar retailers. Today is the day ecommerce websites display their best sales to get customers to buy gifts from them. Smaller retailers can choose to list a major Black Friday + Cyber Monday sale that runs throughout the entire weekend, or flash sales that encourage customers to shop at specific times. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/09/calendar_december-1024x876.jpg" alt="calendar_december" width="700" height="598" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19339" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">December</h2>
<p><strong>Hanukkah</strong> &#8211; (Dec 6th &#8211; Dec 14th) Although this is a religious holiday, today  it’s common to receive a either different gift on each or simply one large gift on the last day of this celebration. Gifts can range from the traditional items to unorthodox mainstream ones.  If you’re decorating your website, keep in mind that Hanukkah colors are blue and white.</p>
<p><strong>Christmas Day</strong> &#8211; (Dec 25th) For Christians and non-Christians alike, Christmas has evolved into a holiday that celebrates family. It’s a time for exchanging gifts among friends and family. </p>
<p><strong>New Year’s Eve</strong> &#8211; (Dec 31st) Every family welcomes the new year in its own way. Some throw parties that go on all night, while others prefer a quiet dinner with the family. New Year’s is not generally celebrated with gift giving but can be a great opportunity to promote products that celebrate a new beginning. </p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">Preparing for the holidays</h2>
<p>Now that you know which holidays you want to plan for, determine which types of sales you want to run. Select the products you want to feature. There are a couple common tactics such as seasonal goods, top sellers, gift-friendly products or even highest margin. </p>
<p>Once you’ve decided o n the products, it’s important to decide on how you want to promote them. For example, would you be using <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-pop-ups-for-your-online-store-best-practices-and-examples-for-2015/">pop-ups or pop-ins to engage your customers</a>? Or would you send out <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/">email newsletters</a> to advertise your sale? Regardless of which method you select, be sure you have enough time to set up your back office. </p>
<p>Not sure what is the best option for your store? Contact any of our module advisors on <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">Addons.PrestaShop.com</a>.  Already a seasoned pro? Share your tips below!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/">Countdown to the holidays</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/countdown-holidays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are you ready to be an entrepreneur?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 15:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20605</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Being an entrepreneur is an exciting prospect for many people, but it’s also a high-risk occupation. We’ve come up a with a few questions to consider before you take the plunge and launch your own business. For a more in-depth idea of what goes into building a business, download our How to Write a Business [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/">Are you ready to be an entrepreneur?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Being an entrepreneur is an exciting prospect for many people, but it’s also a high-risk occupation. We’ve come up a with a few questions to consider before you take the plunge and launch your own business. For a more in-depth idea of what goes into building a business, download our How to Write a Business Plan ebook.<br />
<span id="more-20605"></span></p>
<h2>1. Why do you want to start a business?</h2>
<p>If your answer to this question is “I hate my job,” “I hate my boss,” or “I need a change,” then you should reconsider starting a business. Those are all good reasons to look for a new job or consider a different career path, but not to take on the risk and responsibility associated with starting a business. If you’re answer is something more like “I’m an expert in my field, I’ve got an idea that solves a problem and I’ve done my research,” then you’re on the right track.</p>
<h2>2. Do you have a problem?</h2>
<p>You can’t have a business without a problem, specifically a consumer problem. Does your idea address a specific need? Whose? The fundamental questions of what your product or service does and for whom, will form the basis for your business. You can’t start a business based on a vague “idea” or “market.” You need to offer unique value to your customers. Make sure you know exactly what this is before you launch anything.</p>
<h2>3. Are you passionate?</h2>
<p>Building a company is a long term effort, a lifetime in some cases. The road is not always easy, and it’s your passion and motivation that will keep you searching for solutions and plugging away when the going gets tough. When you start your own business, you’re trading in your 9-5 job for a 24/7 occupation&#8211;and if you love what you do, you won’t feel like you’re working.</p>
<h2>4. Are you disciplined?</h2>
<p>There’s a romantic image of the entrepreneur toiling away late into the night, putting all her energy into building a successful business. The reality is, if you don’t make time for exercise, a healthy diet and most important of all, sleep, you can kiss your dreams of long-term success goodbye. Growing a company requires exceptional time-management skills. You’ll need them to get your business goals accomplished and ensure that you carve out time for the other things in your life, like, you know, your family, friends, sleeping in on the occasional Sunday morning&#8230;</p>
<h2>5. Do you know what you’re doing?</h2>
<p>Ever heard the saying, “Write what you know?” The same holds true for business. It’s hard to envision obstacles and solutions for overcoming them when you have no idea what you’re doing. It’s hard to convince investors to believe in you if you come across as a novice. And it’s difficult to stay motivated when you feel lost at every turn. Many successful entrepreneurs spend years accumulating experience in an industry or honing specific business skills before deciding to the cut the connection with the stability of the good ol’ 9 to 5.</p>
<h2>6. Have you done your research?</h2>
<p>It’s one thing to dream up a company in your head and quite another to build one in the real world. Second in importance only to having an idea that solves a real consumer problem, is market research and financial planning. How big is the market for your product(s)? Who are your competitors? What kind of financial investment will you have to make &#8211; are you able to make? Don’t let these questions extinguish the burning desire you have to start a company; they’re simply there to make sure you don’t burn out before you have a chance to succeed.</p>
<hr />
Whether you’re ready to quit your day job and join the ranks of PrestaShop’s entrepreneurial community or still trying to figure out if running a company is really your thing, our ebook How to Write a Business plan will get you asking the right questions.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a style="font-size: 30px;" href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-business-plan"><strong>Download it for free!</strong></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/">Are you ready to be an entrepreneur?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ready-entrepreneur/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What PrestaShop retailers need to bear in mind when selling goods within the EU (Belgium, France, Great Britain and Switzerland)</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 13:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hagen Meischner]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20615</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Many online retailers believe that when selling goods in an EU country, they can simply apply the legislation of their own country, even if they are aware that, in principle, the law of the supply country applies. In simple terms, they believe that this somehow also includes Switzerland. However, it is not as simple as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/">What PrestaShop retailers need to bear in mind when selling goods within the EU (Belgium, France, Great Britain and Switzerland)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many online retailers believe that when selling goods in an EU country, they can simply apply the legislation of their own country, even if they are aware that, in principle, the law of the supply country applies. In simple terms, they believe that this somehow also includes Switzerland. However, it is not as simple as that. While Brussels has simplified the rules for online trading within the EU by providing a host of guidelines, special national provisions which must be complied with still exist for France, Belgium and Great Britain, for example. And then there’s the legal situation in Switzerland, which is not an EU country and has its own specific legislation.</p>
<p><span id="more-20615"></span></p>
<p>In this post, we will start by explaining the legal situation in EU supply countries (Belgium, France and Great Britain), followed by the legal situation in Switzerland. For an online retailer, the most important aspects to consider are the provisions governing the conclusion of contracts, general terms and conditions, pricing law, warranty regulations and mandatory use of the national languages. The right to withdraw has been fully harmonized in EU countries and, therefore, does not need to be explained. The exception to this is, of course, Switzerland, where EU law does not apply.</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">France</h2>
<p>France intervenes heavily in defining the contractual freedom of retailers, especially in terms of consumer protection.</p>
<p>In France, a product description in a retailer&#8217;s online shop must be viewed as a binding <strong>contractual offer</strong>. To give a practice example, a retailer is bound to honor even inaccurate price information. The mandatory information that online retailers must display in their online shops is harmonized throughout the EU. However, France goes a step further by requiring online retailers <strong>to inform</strong> consumers <strong>of the provisions of warranty law</strong> in their <strong>general terms and conditions</strong>. They may be fined should they fail to do so.</p>
<p>The provisions of <strong>pricing law</strong> are relatively strict. Hence, mandatory detailed rules apply to price discounts on sale items. The competition authorities may punish infringements with heavy fines.</p>
<p><strong>France’s consumer warranty law provisions</strong> are similar to the EU standard. However, from 2016, the burden of proof rule relating to the existence of a defect on reception of goods, which places the responsibility on online retailers, is due to be amended. Until now, EU directives considered that the defect already existed at the time the goods were received, if the defect arose within 6 months and was reported to the online retailer. From 2016, this period will be extended to 2 years.</p>
<p>This represents a significant problem for online retailers: when a defect is reported, they must prove within 6 months that the problem occurred after the customer received the goods, if they wish to defend themselves against consumer claims. This may prove very difficult, or even impossible, in certain cases. Added to that is France’s two-tier warranty law which stipulates that consumers are able to lodge claims on hidden defects. However, the buyer must always provide proof of a hidden defect. With the new law, the two-year warranty period only commences when the defect is discovered and not when the goods are delivered.</p>
<p>Finally, in France, <strong>the French language is mandatory to the creation of an online shop</strong> and infringements may be punished by fines. Furthermore, consumers may invoke the fact that they did not understand information e.g. relating to the right to cancel, if it is not written in French, which grants a one-year right to cancel.</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">Belgium</h2>
<p>Belgium is (at least from a French point of view) the little sister of France. Many Belgian rules concerning online trading are similar to those in France.</p>
<p>However, in Belgium, unlike in France, product descriptions in <strong>online shops are not seen as binding contractual offers</strong> for online retailers. Belgian law is relatively strict regarding the <strong>validity of</strong> online retailers&#8217; <strong>general terms and conditions</strong>. Online retailers must ensure that Belgian customers are only able to complete the ordering process once they have declared that they have read and accepted the general terms and conditions. Otherwise, the general terms and conditions do not apply to the purchase of goods.</p>
<p>The language issue is particularly important in Belgium. Belgium has three official languages, so online retailers should provide an &#8220;opt-in&#8221; clause for application of the general terms and conditions in French, Dutch and German. Retailers&#8217; mandatory information, which they must display on their websites, must be presented in a specific format in Belgium. Where there is no right to cancel, online retailers must insert the following statement in bold on their websites (in the three official languages): &#8220;The buyer does not have the right to withdraw from the sale/purchase&#8221;. If this information is not visible, buyers will be treated as if they have a right to withdraw.</p>
<p>The rules governing <strong>pricing law</strong>, particularly for sale items, are similar to those in France. In terms of <strong>price labeling</strong>, Belgian law specifically stipulates that shipping/delivery costs must be included in the price. The provisions of <strong>warranty law</strong> are similar to those in France. And of course using the official language is mandatory in Belgium, which becomes particularly complex given that there are three official languages (French, Dutch, German).</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">Great Britain</h2>
<p>Great Britain is the antithesis of France, so to speak. British law has significantly less influence over the contractual freedom of online retailers. A retailer-friendly approach is adopted regarding the conclusion of contracts and the validity of general terms and conditions.</p>
<p>However, the situation is different when it comes to <strong>pricing law</strong> and <strong>warranty law</strong>.</p>
<p>Online retailers can offer price discounts, but only if they refer to a comparison price (the online retailer&#8217;s previous price, another retailer&#8217;s price, the recommended retail or manufacturer&#8217;s price). Special discounts for sale items and introductory prices should not apply for longer than a month.</p>
<p>The provisions of <strong>warranty law</strong> are similar to the EU standard. However, in British law, there is no difference between used and new goods. Consumer warranty claims are subject to a limitation period of 6 years (5 years in Scotland) following the receipt of goods.</p>
<h2 style="color: #27a9c3">Switzerland</h2>
<p>Switzerland is not an EU country and has its own contract law, which is more retailer-friendly. Specific characteristics apply to mandatory information, the right to cancel, pricing law, product liability law and import legislation.</p>
<p>Switzerland does not require any comprehensive <strong>pre-contractual information</strong> regarding the web presence of online retailers as is the case in Germany. However, in many respects, Switzerland has adopted EU standards, meaning that it is advisable to apply the usual EU standard information requirements when supplying goods to Switzerland. There is no <strong>right to cancel</strong> as there is in the EU.</p>
<p>Swiss <strong>price labeling</strong> law is very strict and complicated. In principle, the final price, including taxes and customs duties, must be shown. However, because of complicated Swiss customs law, this is barely possible without professional help.</p>
<p>In Switzerland, <strong>advertising with price discounts</strong> is subject to strict rules. Online retailers must display a comparison price, which they have previously applied or refer to a comparison price, which competitors have charged. In the case of a comparison price based on their own previous price, a 2-month discount period applies.</p>
<p>As far as <strong>product liability</strong> is concerned, online retailers can import goods which comply with EU guidelines from the EU into Switzerland. However, there are numerous exceptions, meaning that online retailers should seek professional advice. This applies specifically to product groups, which are subject to a <strong>Swiss import ban</strong> (including, for example, foodstuffs, precious metals and animal products). In this case too, professional advice is essential.</p>
<h4 style="color: #27a9c3">About the author:</h4>
<p>Max-Lion Keller is a lawyer and partner in the law firm IT-Recht in Munich, which specializes in the field of e-commerce law. IT-Recht already protects several thousand online shop operators with its dissuasion secured legal texts, meaning that it is the market leading law firm in terms of continuous support for online retailers.</p>
<p>In addition, as part of its cost-effective general terms &amp; conditions maintenance service, IT-Recht provides dissuasion secured legal texts for numerous domestic and foreign online platforms: <a href="http://www.it-recht-kanzlei.de/Service/rechtstexte_fuer_onlineshops.php" target="_blank">http://www.it-recht-kanzlei.de/Service/rechtstexte_fuer_onlineshops.php</a></p>
<p>To obtain more information on the implementation of the EU standard in Version 1.6.1 of PrestaShop, simply visit our corresponding <strong>Blog Article</strong> or download your free copy of <strong>PrestaShop</strong>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/">What PrestaShop retailers need to bear in mind when selling goods within the EU (Belgium, France, Great Britain and Switzerland)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-retailers-need-bear-mind-selling-goods-within-eu-belgium-france-great-britain-switzerland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ins and Outs of Warranties and Returns Policies for Ecommerce Stores</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20590</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today our guest writer Leah Hamilton, at TermsFeed, is going to clarify a few important aspects of legal policies that ecommerce business owners need to be aware of. When setting up your ecommerce store, you’re most likely concerned about how you’re going to market and price your product, what your website and branding will look [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/">The Ins and Outs of Warranties and Returns Policies for Ecommerce Stores</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Today our guest writer Leah Hamilton,  at TermsFeed, is going to clarify a few important aspects of legal policies that ecommerce business owners need to be aware of.</em></p>
<p>When <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2014/09/05/3-steps-to-launch-your-first-ecommerce-website/" target="_blank">setting up your ecommerce store</a>, you’re most likely concerned about how you’re going to market and price your product, what your website and branding will look like, and setting up various kinds of software, such as shopping carts and payment processing.</p>
<p><span id="more-20590"></span></p>
<p>The <em>last</em> thing on your mind is probably legal policies, especially ones concerning problems or customer returns. But these policies are very important: setting up good warranties and a returns policy that’s in line with the law can save you a lot of strife once your shop is up and running.</p>
<p>In this post, I’m going to go through what these documents are, what they should cover, and how to make sure yours are in line with the law. This article is intended to provide general advice only. If you have any specific questions relating to your business, speak with a lawyer.</p>
<p>Now let’s begin! First, let’s take a look at warranties and returns policies, and then we’ll go through the key sections that need to appear in each.</p>
<h2>What are Warranties and Returns Policies?</h2>
<h4>Warranties</h4>
<p>At its most basic, a <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/w/warranty.asp" target="_blank">warranty is a promise</a> you make about a particular item, such as how long it will last or what condition it will be in when you receive it. Warranties fall into two categories: express and implied.</p>
<p><strong>Express warranties</strong> are used around the world to explicitly promise how goods will perform and their condition. In an express warranty, you might tell your customers that you will repair or replace an item if it breaks within 1 year of sale. Or you might guarantee that the baby carriers you sell can hold up to 20kg. These are both examples of express warranties. If your customer relies on this statement as part of their purchase, you are legally bound as the store owner to ensure that your products respect the warranty conditions.</p>
<p>In the US, all new goods come with two <strong>implied warranties</strong>: the warranty of merchantability (which promises that the goods are what they’re advertised to be); and the warranty of fitness for purpose, (which promises that the goods do what you said they would do). These implied warranties can be excluded by way of a disclaimer, such as:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“The seller undertakes no responsibility for the quality of goods except as otherwise provided in this contract.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Or …</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“The seller assumes no responsibility that goods will be fit for any particular purpose for which you may be buying these goods, except as otherwise provided in the contract.”</em></p>
<h4>Laws and Regulations on Warranties</h4>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnuson%E2%80%93Moss_Warranty_Act" target="_blank">Magnuson-Moss Warranty Act</a> requires store owners to include implied warranties if any other written warranty is offered. This means that if you make any express warranty that the goods will last for a particular period of time, or offer any repairs or refunds, you cannot disclaim the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for purpose. If you exclude the implied warranties and do not give provide any express warranties, you are not giving your customers much reason to trust you, and this may dissuade them from buying your products. “As is” warranties are not permitted in several states.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gov.uk/accepting-returns-and-giving-refunds" target="_blank">In the UK</a>, you must offer a full refund if an item is faulty, not as described or doesn’t do what it’s supposed to, and customers have up to 6 years to make a claim for an item they’ve purchased. However, <a href="http://www.thisismoney.co.uk/money/bills/article-1677034/Two-year-warranty-EU-law.html" target="_blank">the likelihood of the customer being able to get that type of refund dramatically reduces 6 months after they’ve purchased the item</a>: past the initial 6 months, it falls on the buyer to prove that an item was faulty at time of purchase.</p>
<p>A customer has the same right to free repairs or a replacement whether they have a warranty or guarantee, or not. So you may still have to repair or replace goods if a customer’s warranty or guarantee has run out &#8211; or even if you didn’t give a warranty. It’s a good idea to define a clear policy outlining what warranties you offer and do not offer, and ensure that you comply with local laws.</p>
<h4>Returns Policy</h4>
<p>A returns policy might be combined with your warranties, or it might be a separate document. Usually the warranty sets out what is covered, while the returns policy simply defines how you will deal with customer returns and refunds.</p>
<p>The reasons for returns and exchanges are many and varied: a customer may not like the product, or perhaps the product arrived broken, or didn’t perform as advertised. If a product’s warranty is violated (e.g. you sold some spray deodorant cans but none of the sprayers worked, so they weren’t fit for purpose) US law requires that the warranty be honored with a repair or replacement.</p>
<p>Now let’s take a look at what you need to cover when you set up your warranties and returns policy.</p>
<h2>How to Draft a Warranty</h2>
<p>You should first ensure that your goods comply with the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for purpose. If you want to exclude these implied warranties, you can do so by using a disclaimer.</p>
<p>Your warranty should cover:</p>
<ul>
<li>What products are covered by the warranty and what products are not</li>
<li>The length of the warranty period</li>
<li>How you will respond if the goods are not fit for purpose or merchantable</li>
<li>Options for the customer to send or bring in the item for repair, replacement or refund</li>
</ul>
<p>You can offer longer-term or more comprehensive warranties as a way to build goodwill and show excellent customer service.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at an example from Apple.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/legal_01.png" alt="Apple" /><br />
<em>Image: Apple iPhone Warranty (<a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html" target="_blank">https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html</a>)</em></p>
<p>You can see that Apple puts consumer law considerations at the top of their warranty, so that the buyer is immediately informed that the warranty does not limit their rights under applicable laws. The warranty also clearly defines what is covered and what is not covered. Often customers are required to have met certain conditions before the warranty will be upheld. For example, you could require your customers to provide proof of purchase before you agree to provide warranty service.</p>
<p>Here’s an example of Apple’s terms where they also address customer responsibilities and what Apple will do if the warranty is breached:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/legal_02.png" alt="Apple" /><br />
<em>Image: Apple iPhone Warranty (<a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html" target="_blank">https://www.apple.com/legal/warranty/products/ios-warranty-document-us.html</a>)</em></p>
<h2>What Your Returns Policy Should Cover</h2>
<p>Your Returns Policy will need to cover a number of things, such as time limits, amount that you are willing to refund (e.g. full purchase price), types of refunds (such as direct refund, store credit or replacement), and who covers the cost of delivery. Different jurisdictions have different laws on these issues &#8211; the UK differs from the US, and within the US laws differ state by state, and so on.</p>
<p>Your Returns Policy should cover both returns and refunds, and establish:</p>
<ul>
<li>Which items can be returned or refunded, and which can’t (e.g. digital downloads can’t be returned, but can be refunded)</li>
<li>Any time limits on returns or refunds (this will tie in to any warranty periods)</li>
<li>What form the refund will take (e.g. cash, exchange, store credit)</li>
<li>Who is responsible for the shipping cost of physical items</li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s a visual example of the Apple Returns Policy:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/08/legal_03.png" alt="Apple" /><br />
<em>Image: Apple Store Returns Policy (<a href="http://www.apple.com/shop/help/returns_refund" target="_blank">http://www.apple.com/shop/help/returns_refund</a>)</em></p>
<p>Your policy should reflect the laws you are required to abide by in your jurisdiction. For instance, in the UK you must give your customer a refund if your product is broken or faulty, does not match the product description, or doesn’t do what it’s supposed to. So there’s no point writing a policy in the UK that says “No refunds for faulty products” when by law you are required to give a refund.</p>
<p>The UK also has “distance selling” laws that say you must provide a refund if the customer requests one <a href="https://www.gov.uk/accepting-returns-and-giving-refunds" target="_blank">within 14 days</a> of receiving the product, for any reason.</p>
<p>There are also laws that dictate how to display your policy.</p>
<p>For example, California law requires you to clearly display your return and refund policies unless you offer full cash refund, exchange or store credit, within seven days of the purchase date. If you don’t display your policy customers are allowed to return the goods for a full refund within 30 days, no matter what your policy says.</p>
<p>In Florida, you must clearly display your Return/Refund Policy if it does not allow refunds; if you don’t, customers may return goods for a full refund within 20 days of purchase.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Having good warranties and a returns and refunds policy for your ecommerce store is important for keeping your sales practices in line with the law. Ensure that you know your local legal obligations and display any policies and warranties prominently and clearly for your customers.</p>
<p>If you don’t currently have a Returns and Refunds Policy for your ecommerce store, <a href="https://termsfeed.com/return-refund-policy/generator/" target="_blank">visit TermsFeed to create one</a>. TermsFeed allows you to create custom legal agreements online, for your ecommerce website or app. The agreements are completely free, but TermsFeed also offers premium options if you wish to use them. TermsFeed’s agreements are drafted by professional lawyers from around the world, and each agreement goes through a rigorous quality certification process. Check out their <a href="https://termsfeed.com/" target="_blank">agreement generators</a> and <a href="https://termsfeed.com/reviews" target="_blank">testimonials</a>!</p>
<p>To add your Warranties and Returns and Refunds Policy to your footer, you’ll need to add CMS pages to your PrestaStore. Have a look at <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-complete-guide-to-create-cms-pages-for-your-online-store/">this handy guide</a> for how to do so.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/">The Ins and Outs of Warranties and Returns Policies for Ecommerce Stores</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ins-outs-warranties-returns-policies-ecommerce-stores/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
